#### **PROFILE & VALUE**

Entrepreneurial, driven professional with 15+ years of industry experience full-stack architecting, developing and marketing web and software products. Extensive experience with software systems which require deep understanding of critical business requirements; highly successful in building relationships with upper-level decision makers, seizing control of critical problem areas, and delivering on customer commitments.

- Owned, operated and scaled a web development consultancy for 12 years providing a variety of B2B and B2C solutions for companies of all sizes.
- Established and managed product development teams, driving organizational improvements and implementing best practices.
- Led strategic development and delivery of an international testing certification system for enterprise customers.
- Strategized and developed an automated system that brought millions of retail products online and increased online customer sales by 50%.
- Experience in a variety of management methodologies including Agile, Kanban, SCRUM and Waterfall.

# **TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE**

- Highly proficient in a broad range of languages including C#, Node.js, Javascript, Typescript, PHP, VB, HTML, SASS, CSS, XML, XSL, MySQL, SQL and NoSQL (Mongo, CouchDB)
- Familiar with and have used a range of front-end and back-end frameworks in production including: Angular, Express.js, Core MVC, Wordpress, Xamarin, Knockout, jQuery
- Experienced with Unit Testing and related frameworks (MSUnit, NUnit, xUnit), automated build systems (CruiseControl.net, TeamCity), and writing build scripts.
- Intermediate knowledge of C++ and Python.
- Server administration for Linux/Apache and Windows/IIS systems including provisioning web hosting systems, managing AWS and Azure environments, managing DNS, configuring firewalls, configuring proxies and CDNs.
- Hobby interest in developing Ethereum smart contracts, microcontroller applications (Arduino/Raspberry Pi), and home automation.

### **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

# Riddle Brothers Web Design and Development

President

Baltimore, MD 2006 – Present

Own and operate an agile Web and mobile development consultancy specializing in lean product development, backend management systems, e-commerce sites, and custom Web and mobile (iOS/Android) applications. Manage new and existing client relationships; provide technical support to customers; market services to client leads; and manage projects throughout the entire development lifecycle.

**Black Label** 

Partner Baltimore, MD
2015-2017

Managing Partner of a startup digital marketing agency focused on data-driven results including SEO, digital advertising, content marketing, website design and development, project management, and social media marketing. Identified agency's market fit in a competitive industry, developed sales pipeline, recruited and lead Account Services team members, brought agency from \$0 to \$400,000 annual contract value in two years while maintaining a 20% net profit margin.

Bitsie

CEO/Co-founder

Baltimore, MD 2012-2014

Cofounding member of a technology startup that enabled businesses to accept Bitcoin as a form of payment. Managed all facets of company operations from marketing and sales to product development. Lead product team and programmed web applications, mobile apps, financial backend integrations and other utilities for multiple company products. Developed multiple press opportunities (print, online and television) for company.

Planit, Inc.

Application Developer

Baltimore, MD 2006 - 2007

Worked in a 12-15 member team system on multiple projects as a Web and application developer; integrated backend systems into existing frontend designs; developed internal applications to increase employee efficiency and report financial data to accounting team; represented development team in client proposal meetings.

# **FORMAL EDUCATION**

**Howard Community College** 

Business Entrepreneurship Program

**UMBC CCTC** Baltimore, MD A+ Certification Program

Villa Julie College

Computer Information Systems

Stevenson, MD 2001-2003

Columbia, MD

2005-2006

2004